## Yongzhe (Brian) Wang

Phone: +1 604-551-9086

Email: yongzhe.wang@alumni.ubc.ca Location: Vancouver, BC, Canada

<u>Introduction:</u> An agile developer with experience working with automated testing frameworks, with a specific emphasis on writing automated test scripts, regression testing as well as creating comprehensive test cases from scratch.

## **Work Experience:**

# Desire2Learn (Co-op/Intern) – Richmond, BC, Canada Position: QA Developer

May. 2014 – Dec. 2014

- Created, executed, and debugged original test cases for D2L software products and specific features using Python with the Selenium testing tool.
- Upgraded and updated defunct and outdated test cases used for regression testing for those same products.
- Wrote, from scratch, a comprehensive and thorough test plan for testing the software.
- Executed and performed thorough manual tests and regression tests on the software,
  ensuring compatibility with different browsers across various different operating systems.
- Reported defects both to the internal defect reporting system (Rally) as well as supervisors while working in an agile environment.

## IBM (Co-op/Intern) – Victoria, BC, Canada Position: QA Automation Engineer

Jan. 2014 – Apr. 2014

- Created original automated tests for IBM software products and some specific features using
  Java with the Selenium testing tool.
- Upgraded and updated defunct and outdated test cases used for regression testing for those same products.
- Executed and debugged automated tests, ensuring compatibility with different browsers.
- Reported defects both to the internal defect reporting system (RTC) as well as supervisor.

#### **Education:**

#### University of British Columbia, Vancouver. B.Sc. Computer Science

Sep. 2011 – Dec. 2016

- 3.75/4.33 GPA (A- average). Graduated December 2016.
- Course highlights: software engineering, relational databases, algorithmic design and analysis, intelligent systems, human computer interactions (UX/UI).
- Semester study abroad at ETH Zurich in Switzerland (Feb Sep. 2016) with a focus on web development and program management.

## **Select Projects:**

## **Responsive Wordpress Theme (Group)**

- Created a website from scratch using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, using a picture of a design as reference.
- Site was then ported into a customizable and responsive WordPress theme using PHP and jQuery that had to be adaptable to all browser resolutions as well as being mobile-friendly.

#### **GWT Pet Finder Web Application (Group)**

- Designed and implemented a Google Web Toolkit web application using Java with the purpose of creating a local pet finder for lost pets within the Vancouver area.
- Parsed data from a JSON file of known lost pets with descriptions and locations which was then put on a database that was searchable and browsable.
- Integrated share with Facebook functionality as well as Google maps plotting functionality.

### C++ Questionnaire Game

- Designed and implemented a C++ turn based questionnaire game similar to the format of the popular show "Who Wants To Be A Millionaire".
- Featured randomized questions as well as a working 50/50 lifeline option.

#### **Technical Skills:**

**Languages**: Java (2 study terms + 1 work term), Python (2 work terms), C++ (2 study terms), SQL (2 study terms)

**Web**: Selenium (3 work terms), JavaScript (2 study terms), HTML/CSS (2 study term), PHP (1 study term)

Frameworks: Android, Wordpress (1 study term)

**Version Control**: Git (3 work terms), RTC (1 work term)

Others: Photoshop, Office, Axure

## **Interests:**

**Esports:** active follower of current eSports and gaming news; former news writer for ESEA news for over a year and a half.

**Others:** NFL, NBA, NHL, HBO/Showtime/AMC/Netflix dramas.

<sup>\*</sup>No sponsorship required.